# 1 2 走
One, two, go!
# 展现了淮扬菜的老菜叫
This dish presents the cooking technique of a traditional Huaiyang dish
# 扣三丝的手法.0
which is named 'Kou San Si'
# 结合了一个萝卜丝鲫鱼汤
While the other part of this dish is from 'Carp soup with shredded radish'
# 看着啊
Look
# 就要这一瞬间
That's the key moment
# 俩菜组合
The combination of two dishes
# 群英荟萃
Gathering of heroes
# 先处理鲫鱼
Let's deal with the carp first
# 鳍都要铰掉
Cut off the fins with scissor
# 它的牙非常非常腥
The teeth are extremely fishy
# 里边还有好多血水
There's quite a lot of blood in it too
# 表皮黏液腥味太重
The skin mucus also smells very fishy
# 而且夹杂了很多细菌
and has a lot of bacteria
# 所以这我们要用80度左右的水
So we need to use hot water at about 80 degrees Celsius
# 要烫一下
to 'wash' it
# 咱们用刀刮一下
Let's scratch it with a knife
# 看这水 你要不擖饬
Look at the water. If you don't wash it
# 你看看 脏成什么样了
Look how dirty it is
# 里边那些杂质处理下来
The impurities are removed
# 又出了很多
There's a lot (of dirty stuff)
# 这要溶解到汤里边
If these impurities dissolve in the soup
# 跟刷锅水似的
The soup will be like dishwater
# 你看这鱼多干净
Look how clean the fish are
# 干干净净
So clean
# 清澈见底
So clear that you can see the bottom of the bowl
# 好 下一步
Ok. Next
# 打花刀
Cut the fish
# 这个打花刀也很重要
Scoring is also important
# 没事打狠一点
It's ok. Score deeper
# 因为咱们只用汤
Because we just need the soup
# 花刀打完之后
After scoring
# 它便于它的一个成熟
The fish will be cooked much faster
# 好
Okay
# 煎鱼
Fry the fish
# 对 热锅凉油
Yes. Hot wok, cold oil
# 放点葱油还有色拉油
Add some green onion oil and regular oil
# 这就是老方法 二合油
That's a traditional technique. Mixed oil
# 放两片姜
Two slices of ginger
# 把这姜煸的的有点香味
Fry the ginger until aromatic
# 然后把鱼放进去
Then put the fish in
# 大火煎
Fry it with high heat
# 先不着急动
Don't touch it for now
# 这个鱼只有把它肉煎熟了之后
The fish... only after the fish is completely cooked
# 那么再加入热水
you can add hot water
# 汤才能浓白
The soup will be thick and milky white in this way
# 鱼皮经过热处理之后
The fish skin... after washed with hot water
# 刮掉表面黏膜
and removing the mucus
# 这个皮就很少了 几乎没有了
The skin is almost gone
# 所以在煎的时候就很容易会脱落
Hence the fish falls apart easily when frying
# 好 呲水
Okay. Add hot water
# 就要这一瞬间
That's the key moment
# 搁点黄酒
Add some Huangjiu rice wine
# 料酒去腥
Wine removes the fishy odor
# 还得打打沫子
Remove the scum as well
# 滚白了 滚白了为止 一刻钟
Boil until the soup turns white. 15 minutes
# 这个鱼汤我们煮着
While boiling the fish soup
# 这个萝卜丝咱们用三种颜色
Let's prepare three types of shredded radish
# 一个是白萝卜
White radish
# 胡萝卜 还有青萝卜
Carrot, and green radish
# 萝卜开会真来了啊
That's radishes having a meeting
# 先切片
Slice first
# 这切完之后呢
After slicing
# 一会咱们要先焯水
We need to blanch them first
# 因为如果我们要码盘
Since we want to present the dish in a beautiful way
# 先切完丝儿再焯水
If we blanch after shredding
# 那就不好码了
Presenting the dish will be very difficult
# 咱们这水里边要放点盐
Add some salt into the water
# 冷水热水都问题不是很大
It doesn't matter if you use cold or hot water
# 但是一定要让它迅速的开锅
But you should make sure it boils quickly
# 时间长了
If it boils slowly
# 把那萝卜就煮烂掉了
The radishes will be too soft
# 然后也是不能盖盖
Also, don't close the lid
# 行了 萝卜一开汤儿
Done. As soon as it boils
# 汤现在已经开始变白
The fish soup is turning white
# 还没达到要求
But not white enough yet
# 里边儿腥味儿比较大
It still smells fishy
# 咱们搁两片儿 葱姜
Let's add some green onion and ginger
# 继续
Go on
# 你看这汤倍儿白
Look. The soup is so white
# 切丝儿
Shred the radish
# 您要觉得切丝难呢
If you feel it's hard to shred the radish with a knife
# 你拿擦丝器擦
You can use a kitchen shredder
# 这鱼汤啊 看看啊
The fish soup. Look
# 鱼汤到一定程度
At some point
# 就把这个肉给它杵烂
You can mash the fish
# 我们只要汤不要肉
We just need the soup. Not the meat
# 该装碗了
Time to put in the bowl
# 下边垫一层保鲜膜
Apply a piece of plastic wrap underneath
# 蒸完之后遇热它好脱
(The dish) will fall out easily from the bowl after steaming
# 这个地方直接摆到
Place the shredded radish
# 碗中心这个部位 不能过中心
to the center of the bowl. Do not go over the center
# 剩下呢 咱们这个萝卜丝
The remaining radish...
# 全部都放到碗底
Put them all at the bottom
# 成型的时候更容易托着
They will hold the dish together
# 不搁这个这中间一个大坑
Otherwise there'll be a big pit
# 为了更加美观
To make it more beautiful
# 把这个边要铰一下
Trim the surroundings
# 扣出来以后
such that when you turn over the bowl
# 边上一圈是圆的
The surrounding can form a circle
# 修边 铰刘海
Trim the surroundings. Just like cutting the bangs
# 找一干净盘
Get a clean plate
# 把这点肉捞出来
Take out the meat
# 在家里边
When cooking at home
# 您要觉得很麻烦的话
If you think this is too complicated
# 您就切点五彩丝儿
Just prepare some shredded radish
# 做个鲫鱼汤往里一放
Make a carp soup and simply put it in
# 你要想变个展示的方法
If you want to change the way of presenting
# 您就按照我这个操作一下
You can follow my steps
# 来 过滤一下
Let's filter it
# 我们把这个鱼汤得调一下味
We need to season the soup
# 然后倒在萝卜丝里
Then pour it into the shredded radish
# 然后上锅得蒸一下
Then steam the dish
# 你看这汤 特别的白
Look at the soup
# 奶白奶白的
Milky white
# 搁点盐
Add some salt
# 这口味得重一点
Make it a bit strong
# 胡椒
Pepper
# 灌上鱼汤
Add some fish soup
# 咱们上锅蒸
Let's steam the dish
# 上气之后咱们蒸上10分钟
Steam for 10 minutes after boiling
# 10分钟足够了
10 minutes is enough
# 因为这萝卜焯过水了
Since we have already blanched the radish
# 时间到了
Time's up!
# 好出锅
Okay. Take it out of the pot
# 关火 关火别烫着了
Turn of the heat. Don't burn yourself
# 别烫着
Careful. Don't burn yourself
# 把这个汤篦一下
Remove the soup
# 它里边有萝卜那个
The soup is contaminated
# 多余的臭气
with the odor of the radish
# 这汤就不要了
Discard the soup
# 翻
Flip it
# 1 2 走
One, two, go!
# 没事没事 掀你的
It's okay. Go ahead
# 没问题
That's perfect
# 防止它把这个丝儿冲乱
To prevent (the soup) from disturbing the shredded radish
# 上面要搁一个罩
We need to 'shield' it
# 蛋皮丝增加颜色
Enrich the color with shredded fried egg
# 把中间刀口盖上
Cover the junction in the middle
# 咱们还有枸杞
Add some wolfberries too
# 这叫封底
That's 'sealing the bottom'
# 群英荟萃
Gathering of heroes
# 一口鲜
A bite of umami taste
# 这个菜还真不一样
This is a unique dish
# 我建议多熬点汤
I suggest to make more soup
# 然后随一大碗汤走
And serve the dish with a large bowl of soup
# 一人来一小碗一盛就完美了
So that (in a banquet) everyone can have a small bowl of soup.
# 这是我跟大爷的一点建议
That's a piece of advice from Da Ye and me
# 谢谢二伯
Thank you, Er Bai
# 谢谢师父
Thanks, master!
# 端出去吧 展示一下
Take it out and show it to everyone
# 品尝一下
Let them taste it